《斯巴达克斯：血与沙》
《暗影游戏》
轮换！
Switch!
Crixus啊！
Crixus!
你没听到我的指令吗？
Did you not hear my instruction?
抱歉 Doctore
Apologies, doctore.
我不是故意去吓胆小鬼的
I did not mean to scare the rabbit.
为了准备行政官主办的竞技赛
The games of the magistrate approach.
你们要认真听清我的指令
Listen carefully to my instruction,
每个被选上的人
And every man chosen
都要在竞技场力保获胜
Will see victory in the arena.
或许保证不了
Perhaps not every man.
Pietros啊
pietros.
把水留给那些值得喝的人
Save the water for men who deserve it.
下雨吧！该死的神啊
Rain! By jupiter's cock,
赶紧下雨吧！
Would you fucking rain!
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
祈祷啊
Praying.
倒像在渎神
Blaspheming.
人要是不爽 这两者也就一线之隔
The two are narrowly separated in these trying times.
或许不止一线哦…
Perhaps the gap widens…
有更多债主 想要逼债？
More creditors, seeking action?
可能看了会让人开心点儿
Something of more cheerful note,
刚收到的…
Recently delivered…
Calavius行政官寄来的！
From magistrate calavius!
他要亲自来这儿
He is coming here to personally
为比赛选人！
Select men for his games!
为了抚慰天神 结束干旱的比赛啊！
Games to appease the gods and end the drought!
这是继Theokoles打败100名角斗士的比赛之后
The biggest games since theokoles
最大型的赛事了！
Bested 100 men in the arena!
但他干嘛亲自来？除非…
But why come himself? Unless…
终极勇士
Thprimus.
如果我们能在这种大赛中稳操胜券…
If we were to secure the main event at these games…
他马上就到
He arrives within the hour.
去准备食物
Prepare food.
把我们所有的水聚集起来
And gather all the water we have.
Quintus 你的袍子…
Quintus, your robe…
呃 没事
Uh, it's nothing.
叫医生来
Fetch the medicus.
Lucretia啊…
Lucretia…
我得告诉行政官
I should talk to the magistrate about it.
那些人想杀你 想杀掉像你这么正直的人
Those men tried to kill you, an honest man.
事发于那种不光彩的地方
In a dishonest place.
别去说 我们不该让行政官在这种琐事上分心
No, we won't concern the magistrate with these things,
这和终极勇士一事相比 简直不值一提
Not with the primus in the balance.
这事我自己会解决的 嗯
I'll tend to the matter myself, um.
这是一个意图刺杀Batiatus的
That was the mark of one of the slaves
奴隶身上的烙印
Who tried to kill batiatus.
我没见过这种烙印
The mark is unknown to me.
或者要靠近点看…
Perhaps a closer look…
这手艺的细节部分
Details of such craftsmanship
一瞥可不够啊
Should not be viewed in haste.
我可能见过一个类似的烙印…
I may have seen a similar mark…
啊
Ahh.
嗯 你觉得怎样？
So, what do you think?
真是人靠衣装啊
You adorn them like a god.
那我脱了它们…
I would be out of them…
和你来场鱼水之欢…
And deep into you…
抱歉打扰
Apologies.
Calavius行政官到了
Magistrate calavius arrives.
我们的财神爷到了 就像你这条鱼一样
Our fortunes rise, like your cock.
那你这滩水就继续淌着吧 回头我们欢个够… 哦
Stay wet and we'll make it rain presently…Ohhh.
行政官！
Magistrate!
您真是让我们蓬荜…
You do us honor with your…
生辉！
Presence!
Batiatus 你好！我正跟Solonius聊到
Good batiatus! I was telling solonius
我是怎么认识你父亲的
How I knew your father.
他可是个真正的罗马勇士
Now there was a true roman.
他可真伟大 他人难以望其项背
A great man, none of his like to follow.
我会像我父亲那样 满足您的一切需要
I will attempt to fill your needs as he would have.
那么 谈正事吧
To business then.
众所周知 干旱已使整座城市
As you well know, the drought has parched the city
濒临崩溃
To the point of madness.
我们用尽一切办法 也没法使上天降雨
We've tried everything to tempted the skies into tears,
简直快成「大灾难」了
Even to the point of hecatombe.
祭了一百头牛 却连一滴雨都没求到
A hundred cattle sacrificed, and yet not a drop.
因为天神不稀罕牛血
Because the gods do not want the blood of cattle.
他们想要人血！
They want the blood of men!
Solonius真不错
Good solonius has been kind enough
他帮忙筹办了这场赛事
To lend a hand in organizing games
来满足天神
To appease their appetite.
这将是一场终极决斗
It will be sine missione.
一定要拼个你死我活 方才罢手
No draw. No mercy shown.
只有最好的角斗士
Only the finest gladiators
才能参加
Will be invited to participate.
Batiatus家族也只会 提供最好的角斗士参赛
Only the finest are offered in the house of batiatus.
来吧 看看我的勇士们
Come, examine my wares.
真是令人印象深刻的人选
An impressive selection,
和Solonius亲自挑的人 有得一拼
Rivaling that of good solonius himself.
我已经有终极勇士了
Yet I have the primus.
一个而已
Half.
你的对手还空着呢
Your opponent still to be chosen.
如果你想要满足天神
If you wish to appease the gods,
你得从那沙地上挑出一位来
You must have one upon the sands
Crixus 卡普亚的战神
Crixus the champion of capua,
愿意和Solonius选出的任意勇士一战
Will willing fight anyone that solonius has to offer.
棒极了！
Excellent!
这将是传奇人物之间的竞技！
It will truly be a contest between legends!
传奇人物？
Legends?
哦 我未曾向你提及吗？
Oh, did I fail to mention?
Solonius已派出Theokoles 作为终极勇士压阵！
Good solonius has secured theokoles for the primus!
Theokoles吗？
theokoles?
我为了把他哄来卡普亚城
I managed to coax him to our fair city,
可花了不少钱呢
At great expense.
真是多谢了
With our gratitude.
如此这般进贡祈求 若神明仍未赐雨
If the gods fail to grant us rain with such a tribute,
必是我们遭到天谴
Then we are surely cursed.
我怕触怒神明呢
I fear the gods will be displeased.
这场较量 对比悬殊
The match is unbalanced.
以前与Theokoles竞技的角斗士中
Only one man theokoles
仅有一人得以存活
And lived.
若是Crixus和斯巴达克斯携手出战 又将如何？
What if crixus were joined by your man spartacus?
他早就该死了
His death was fated in execution,
但他却逃过一劫
Yet he refuse to own it.
与他对战 使我连损四将
And cost me four men in his defiance.
谁不知你债台高筑 Batiatus
Your debts are well known, batiatus.
即使他们战死了
Even if you lose the men,
赚到的钱也足以使你
The purse is enough to hold off your creditors,
暂且拖欠债务
For a moment.
当然 除非你宁愿
Unless of course you would rather
不参赛
Sit out these games
或另派他人参赛…
Or any others that follow, which…
不 我决定派他们出赛
No. I will set my men to the task.
我的勇士们！
My titans!
稍停片刻 听听令人倍感荣耀的消息！
Pause, and hear glorious news!
行政官Titus Calavius 已邀请我们实力最强的人
Magistrate titus calavius has invited our best men
作为终极勇士出战！
To fight in his primus!
Crixus啊！
Crixus!
出列！
Step forward!
斯巴达克斯！出列！
Spartacus! Step forward.
你们已被选定携手迎战…
You have been chosen to fight as one…
死亡之影 Theokoles！
Against theokoles, the shadow of death!
靠！喔！喔！
Fuck! Ow! Ow!
靠！喔！
Fuck! Ow!
他妈的！我靠！
Shit! Fuck!
喔！喔！妈的！
Ow! Ow! Shit!
靠！喔！喔！
Fuck! Ow! Ow!
相信你们会成为一对完美搭档
I think you two will make a fine couple.
我可不愿与他一起出战
I'd rather fight without him.
或是一起去死
And die the same.
这个Theokoles
This theokoles.
怕是徒有虚名吧
The legends can't be true.
竞技场上 他身经百战
He's en cut a thousand times in the arena,
却未尝败绩
He's never fallen.
你还是乖乖待在竞技赌场的好
I fear you would have been safer in the pits.
我们若是赢了
If we were to win,
能赚多少钱？
How large would be the purse?
足以在叙利亚讨十个老婆了吧
Large enough to wrest ten wives from the syrian.
这是让他们去送死
You send them to certain death.
让我代替他们出战
Let me fight in their stead.
这个建议不错
That's an excellent suggestion.
我欠Theokoles一条命
I owe theokoles a debt of pain.
你无需这么做！
You were not requested!
瞧啊 没人会忘记
Look, no one has forgotten how bravely
你在对战Theokoles时的英勇表现 老朋友
You fought against theokoles, old friend.
可我并未获胜
Yet without victory.
在与Theokoles的竞技中 你是唯一存活下来的角斗士
You stand the only man to face him in the arena and live.
这本身就是一种胜利
That in itself is a victory.
安心完成好你的训练任务吧
Set your purpose to the task of training
让Crixus和斯巴达克斯共同出战
Crixus and spartacus for the match.
他们怕是无法逃脱
I fear no amount will save them
Theokoles的死亡之影了
From the shadow's grasp.
那就让他们准备 为荣耀而死吧
Then prepare them for a glorious death.
这个牌子是Remus的 一个在城北
The brand belonged to remus, a slave trader
进行交易的奴隶商人
Plying wares north of the city.
Remus？怕是无名之辈吧
Remus? The name holds no recognition.
我也这么觉得
Nor to I. Yet,
如果我要购买一个奴隶 来做见不得人的事…
If I were to purchase a slave, intent on foul designs…
那肯定要从卡普亚城外买
Then it would be from outside capua,
以免轻易就被发现
To avoid simple discovery.
找到Remus 带他来见我
Find remus and bring him.
我要跟他谈谈
I would have conversation.
是 主人
Dominus.
水
Water.
主人给的
From domina.
帮助你训练的
To help with your training.
稍等片刻
Wait a moment.
有什么事？
To what purpose?
需要理由吗？
Need there be one?
你不该那样看着我
You shouldn't look at me in that way.
我已经竭尽全力 不这么做了
I try with all my strength not to.
但我现在很虚弱
But I am weak.
那就睡吧
sleep, then.
恢复体力
And regain your strength.
我无意和你争吵
I seek no quarrel.
你出现在这里 就是这意思
Your presence here would state otherwise.
我们确实有分歧
We've had our differences.
我自己也有责任
I own my part in them.
如果我们想要击败Theokoles…
Yet if we are to defeat theokoles…
我们？
We?
在竞技场上 不会发生这种事
There is no such thing in the arena.
你以为 你能杀掉那巨人吗？
You believe you can slay the giant?
凭你自己？
Alone?
像我往常那样
As I always stand.
这次可不行
This time you do not.
Theokoles倒下后 荣耀全是我的
When theokoles falls, the glory will be mine.
如果我们不能一致对外
And if we do not come to common ground,
我们将必死无疑
The death shared will be ours.
哦 似乎他们有机会战胜Theokoles
Oh. As if they stand chance against theokoles.
呃 或许天神会眷顾他们
Um. Perhaps the gods will favor them.
是啊 或许我也可能
Yes, and perhaps I should sprout wings
长翅膀飞走呢
And flutter off.
赌注是1000比1 赌Theokoles赢
The odds lay a thousand to one against them.
还没人打败过Crixus呢
No man has ever won betting against crixus.
我会下注赌他们会赢
I would lay coin towards their victory.
真是愚蠢
A fool's wager.
我很乐意接受
Happily received.
一声不吭就要走
You leave without words.
没什么好说的
None to give.
每次你走出这里
Each time you step beyond these walls,
我都会为你担心…
I fear for you and what…
别跟软蛋似的 男人点！
Grab hold of your cock and be a man!
我只做我必须做的 Pietros
I do what I must, pietros.
我速去速回
I'll return soon.
小心点
Mind the birds.
Pietros啊！
Pietros!
把武器给我！
Weapons!
Ilithyia来了？
Ilithyia?
我请她来的
She comes at my invitation.
现在可不是那个被宠坏的
Now's not the time to be entertaining
小荡妇玩的时候
That spoiled little bitch.
行政官对她父亲Albinius言听计从
Her father albinius holds the magistrate's ear.
如果她父亲说点好话
If he were to place a word in it,
Crixus可能就会成为终极勇士
Then crixus may be replaced in the primus.
他就算花上一千 也不会有什么结果
He could place a thousand and to no result.
Solonius在耍你
Solonius maneuvered you.
我们有行政官相助！
With the aid of the magistrate!
如果拒绝的话
Refuse and we would quickly find ourselves
我们很快会被 排除在竞技场之外
Excluded from the arena altogether.
如果Crixus失败了呢？
And if crixus falls?
谁会成为我们的战神？
Who will be our champion?
Batiatus家族还有哪个能赢得民众的呼声？
Who will the crowds clamor to see from the house of batiatus?
别告诉我是斯巴达克斯 竞技赌场的那个？
Not spartacus, that thing from the pits?
你客人到了
Your guest arrives.
别跟她谈这事
Do not broach the subject with her.
Ilithyia啊！
Ilithyia!
您莅临至此 我们荣幸之至
You do us honor with your presence.
如果有水喝 我才不在乎这些呢
I would trade honor for water.
啊 热气灌满了喉咙
Ah, the heat is a thing living, crawling down the throat.
那 让我们先解解渴吧
Well, let us quench that thirst.
我得去处理比赛的事了
I must to tend to business of the games.
你俩慢慢聊
I leave you in loving hands.
真的？什么？
Is it true, then? What?
Crixus和斯巴达克斯对战死亡之影？
Crixus and spartacus face the shadow of death?
对
they do.
那天肯定会鲜血四溅
Blood will surely flow on the day.
我非常希望色雷斯人死掉
I long to see it pour from the thracian.
像个男人一样攻击
You attack as you would a man.
Theokoles没有肉
Theokoles is beyond flesh.
没有骨头和鲜血
Beyond blood and bone.
他主宰着生死
He is the shadow that precedes death.
如果让他独自进攻你…
Allow him to fall upon you alone…
你就死定了
And you are dead.
给我站起来
Now rise,
合二为一 攻击我！
And come at me as one!
让开 混蛋！
Give way, you fuck!
我先来！
The advantage was mine!
看Crixus是怎么攻击的
How crixus moves.
看他那身肌肉…
The way his muscles catch the sun…
卡普亚的冠军 名副其实
Truly the champion of capua.
无人能比
None to his equal.
你们互相推搡 跟白痴一样
You jostle and trip over the other like fools.
你们要面对的是终极勇士Theokoles！
You face theokoles in the primus!
证明自己的价值！
Prove yourselves worthy!
可怜虫
Pathetic.
我要站近点看
I crave a closer look.
我们能下去看吗？
Can we go down among them?
我丈夫不会允许的
My husband would never allow it.
肮脏的训练场可不适合
The bowels of a ludus are no place
议员的女儿呆啊
For a senator's daughter.
在小屋里偷看 怎样？
A private viewing then, in the villa?
我会付钱的
I would pay for it, of course.
就当帮朋友吧
A favor amongst friends.
那你得给我机会 还你人情啊
You must let me return it, then.
我一直惦记着你的问题呢
I've given thought to your problem,
也找到了个解决的方法
And have discovered solution.
问题…？
Problem…?
生孩子
Children.
对啊
Yes.
我听说过一个女人 朱诺女神的祭司
I've heard of a woman, a priestess of juno,
向她祈福 可以多子多女
Blessed with certain gifts of fertility.
许多尊贵的女人都谈到过她
Many prominent women speak of her.
比如Servillia Cornelia Laelia…
Servillia, cornelia, laelia…
Ovidius的妻子？
Ovidius' wife?
你认识她？
You know her?
哦 顺便提一下 她有个儿子
Oh, in passing. She has a small boy.
如果她没去找那个祭司的话
And would have none, if not touched
可能就没有孩子了
By the woman I speak of.
要我帮你引见吗？
Will you let me arrange it for you?
就算回报你的盛情吧？
As a gift for your hospitality?
我们是朋友 对吧？
We are friends, aren't we?
我们是挚友
The very best.
赢不了Doctore 我们怎么跟
How are we to fare against theokoles,
Theokoles较量？
When we cannot even best doctore?
如果你不碍手碍脚的话
I could have bested him a dozen times,
我早就打败他十几次了
If you'd not gotten underfoot.
Crixus 我和你在这场决斗里 是并肩作战的
I take the sands beside you in this fight, crixus.
别只因为你跟我
Just because you stand beside me
并肩作战
With sword and shield,
就把自己当成角斗士了
Do not mistake yourself as a gladiator.
我为荣誉而战 而你为自由而战
I fight to honor these walls, you fight to leave them.
你之所以战斗…
You fight…
是因为 你是个奴隶
Because you are a slave.
和我一样
Like me.
不
No.
不一样
Not like you.
我以我的处境为荣
I accept my place here.
我很享受
I embrace it.
而你…
But you…
你仍然幻想着竞技场外的生活
You still dream of a life beyond the arena.
幻想着你那众所周知的妻子
Where that wife of yours we've all heard about
仍然依偎在你身旁
Is still nestled by your side.
所有的都是梦而已 斯巴达克斯
And that is all it is, spartacus.
总有一天你会清醒地面对现实
A dream and one day soon you will awaken to the truth.
你永远都无法离开这里
You will never leave this place.
你妻子即便还活着
And your wife if she's not dead already,
也已经被罗马人侮辱成疯子了
Has been fucked to madness by a hundred roman cocks.
整理下自己
Get yourselves cleaned up.
主人要召见你们
Domina requests your presence.
你们俩
Both of you.
你知道我是谁吗 色雷斯人？
Do you know who I am, thracian?
说话
Speak.
我见过你
I have seen you.
和Glaber副将一起
With legatus glaber.
我是他妻子
I am his wife.
很遗憾 他出国了
He is regrettably abroad,
不能亲眼目睹 你跟Theokoles的生死对抗了
And will not be able to theokoles.
不过…
But…
当我们在床上缠绵的时候
I shall whisper of it to him,
我会悄悄地
Replaying the moment
将我的所见告诉他
When we are entwined in our bed.
打扰一下
Apologies.
我要和这个色雷斯人单独谈谈
I require the thracian for a moment.
慢慢谈吧
Extend it by a lifetime.
我说完了
I am done with him.
带到我那里去
My office.
卡普亚的战神！
The champion of capua!
能获您的观审 真是殊荣
A rare honor to receive a private audience.
他是我最欣赏的人
One I am most appreciative of.
但是
Although,
这种场合他似乎穿多了
He does seem a touch overdressed for the occasion.
你的裤子 脱了吧
Your subligaria. Remove it.
你的战神真是名不虚传
Your champion is bold to his purpose.
我先走了
I take my leave.
他身体如此结实…
His flesh is so hard…
坚如磐石
Like marble.
谁能有如许雕刻般的…
Would that every man were carved so…
我们最好别让他待在这儿了
We'd best not keep him.
他黎明就要开始训练了
His training resumes at first light.
你觉得他能打败死亡之影 活下来吗？
Do you think he will survive, against the shadow?
只有神灵知道
Only the gods know.
若这样的猛男都死了 那真是太可惜了
It would be pity to see such a man marred.
或许有阻止悲剧发生的方法
Perhaps there is a way to see such a tragedy averted.
如果你父亲和行政官说说
If your father where to speak to the magistrate.
或许… 怎么说？
Perhaps… To what end?
将Crixus从这场比赛中换掉
To seeing crixus replaced in the games.
那是你所希望的吗？
Is that what you want?
和Theokoles一起进竞技场 你会怕吗？
Do you fear entering the arena with theokoles?
我期待已久
I long for it.
正如我所期待的一样
As I long to see it.
你背井离乡 有幸存活
You survived being dragged from your homeland
得益于Glaber副将
By legatus glaber,
你在竞技场打败了四名角斗士 逃过了死刑
You survived execution by four gladiators in the arena.
你甚至逃过了竞技赌场的可怕较量
You even survived the horror of the pits.
你能逃过此劫吗？
Can you survive this?
我和Crixus战斗目的不同
Crixus and I fight at cross-purposes.
那就找个合二为一的办法
Then find a way to unite them.
你或许救了我一命
You may have saved my life,
但你的命在竞技场一文不值
But yours is yet worth little in the arena.
但把你和Crixus一起放了
But to loose crixus along with you
对训练场来说
That would be a blow from which this ludus
会是致命一击
Would not recover.
我在乎的只有我妻子
My concern is only for my wife.
而她的命在于这些高墙
And her fate is tied to these walls.
倘若它们垮了
If they collapse around me,
我自身难保 也救不了她
Then I will be unable to help her from beneath the rubble.
她安全前 我不会死
I will not die until she is safe.
好吧 证明出来
Well, prove it so.
和Crixus并肩作战 打败Theokoles
Fight as one with crixus, to best theokoles.
否则我们都玩儿完了
Or we are all fucked.
没错
Yes.
Barca回来了 满载而归
Barca has returned, bearing gifts.
把他带回营房
Remove him to the barracks.
你卖掉的两个奴隶
Two slaves, broken by your hand,
想要杀了我
Made attempt on my life.
是谁指使他们的？
Who purchased them?
我不知道你在说什么…
I know not of what you speak…
我说的是 我被耍了
I speak of being fucked.
被神 被行政官
By the gods, by the magistrate,
被那个卑鄙的Solonius 和他笑里藏刀的计划所玩弄！
By that cock suck solonius and his grinning schemes!
我有着高贵的血统！
I'm of proud family!
我的家族富裕且源远流长 你个该死的龟孙子！
A family of means and history, you fucking cunt!
你卖了那些人！
You sold the men!
那些普通的奴隶
Common slaves,
想要杀我 想就这样羞辱我！
Who tried to kill me, tried to fuck me like a whore!
但我不会让他们得逞的！
But I will not be fucked!
我！不！会！
I! Will! Not!
不！会！的！
Not! Be! Fucked!
你去死吧…
You fuck you…
你他妈的
You fucking hemorrhoid
去死 你去死！
Sucking fuck, you fuck!
Ovidius啊
Ovidius.
怎么了？
What?
是Ovidius…
Ovidius…
卖…
Sold…
给了Ovidius…
To ovidius…
问个话有那么难？
There was that so fucking hard?
Ovidius的兄弟是行政官
Ovidius' cousin is the magistrate.
他就算和朱庇特称兄道弟又怎样
He could be cousin to jupiter himself,
我连眼皮都懒得抬
I don't give a shit.
我要个满意的结果
I will have satisfaction.
你真让我丢脸
You dishonor me.
色雷斯人阻碍了我的进攻
The thracian impedes my attack.
我力求稳固
I seek to strengthen it.
我不要人帮忙
I seek no aid.
不 你需要神的庇佑
No, you need the gods to descend
助你一臂之力！
And fight by your side!
即使胜利无望
Even then victory is doubtful.
我的话 说了跟没说一样
Words, falling on deaf ears.
睁大眼看看…
Attend your eyes, then…
我的失败
My failure.
你们的教训
Your lesson.
在我以为他很弱…
His first cut…
并傻傻地进行攻击之时
Dealt when I thought him vulnerable.
他给了我第一刀
And pressed my attack unwisely.
他的第二轮攻击…
His next assault…
是在我跌倒之后
Came as I fell back
力求平衡之时袭来的…
To regain position…
然而这些伤痛没什么
Yet these wounds are nothing.
血的游戏 娱乐大众
A game of blood, to amuse the crowd.
当他厌倦游戏
And when he tires of playing,
他会让你脑袋…
He will move to separate your head…
搬家…
From your neck…
我之所以活着 是因为
I live because I survived longer than any man
我比他的任何对手都擅打
That stood against him.
有人认为那是胜利
Some herald that as a victory.
我却不这么看
I am not among them.
你告诉我们 死亡之影在受到压制或
You tell us the shadow wounds both
被打倒在地时 容易受伤
When he is pressed and when he is given ground.
那又该怎么打败他？
How will he to be defeated?
两者皆要同时做到
By accomplishing both at once.
压制他…
Press…
防守
And defend.
引他分神…
Distract…
再进攻
And strike.
并肩作战
Fight as one.
或是一起阵亡
Or die as two.
现在 把荣耀之路指给我看
Now, show me the way to honor.
明天就比赛了 他还给他们施压啊
The games tomorrow, and yet he presses them.
为了他们好
To their benefit.
我在城里有事
I have business in town.
大概要耗到晚上
It'll take me until late into the night.
Lucretia啊
Lucretia.
嗯？
Um?
我有事要办
Business.
对 有事 我听到了
Yeah, business, I heard you.
如果你希望我推迟的话…
If you would prefer I delay…
不 我有节目
No, I have diversion.
Ilithyia和她的女祭司来了
Ilithyia's coming with her priestess.
愿上帝赐予我们奇迹
May the gods grant us miracle.
他们他妈的欠我们的
They fucking owe us something.
一点忠告 斯巴达克斯
A word of advice, spartacus.
要什么好处？
At what cost?
免费放送
Freely given.
别以为你能和Crixus达成协议
Do not think you can come to terms with crixus.
我曾经在竞技场相信过他一次
I've trusted him once in the arena
这就是下场…
And this was the result…
他还不如把我的命根子也切了
He may as well have cut the balls from my shaft.
他会反过来对付自己的盟友？
He'd turn a sword against his ally?
就连Barca也会 如果要他在盟友和荣誉之间选的话
Even barca, if stood between him and glory.
要想从Theokoles手里活着回来 唯一的办法
The only way to survive against theokoles
就是把Crixus也看成一个同等的敌人
Is to consider crixus an equal enemy.
你多长时间性交一次？
How often do you engage in intercourse?
一星期几次
Several times a week.
有时候更多
Sometimes more.
有没有怀过孕？
Has seed ever taken hold?
从来没有
Never.
除了你丈夫之外 还跟其他男人发生过关系吗？
Have there been other men, besides your husband?
那有关系吗？
What bearing does that have?
它可以证明 这是否是正确的结合
Well it will inform the correct combination of elements.
仪式是个人的隐私
The ritual is usually a private matter.
也许…
Perhaps…
求你了 让我留下可以吗？
Oh please, can I stay?
我从来没见过这些
I've never seen one of these.
太有趣了
It's so intriguing.
有吗？
Other men?
有其他的男人吗？
Have there been any?
是的
Yes.
有几个？
How many?
一个 但是经常来
One. But frequently.
那么问题就不在男人身上
Then the difficulty lies not with the seed,
而在你的身上
But within the vessel.
你的意思是说 她生理上有问题？
You mean there's something wrong with her?
神已经决定 拒绝给她天伦之乐
The gods have decided to withhold the joy of children.
但我们会恳求他们 重新考虑…
But we will entreat them to reconsider…
喝吧
Drink.
朱诺女神会保佑你
Juno has blessed you.
你必须在一个小时之内完成结合
You must copulate within the hour.
这么快？
So soon?
在生命之火熄灭前
Before the flame of life expires.
祝你好运
Good fortune be with you.
只有一个小时？
Only an hour?
你认为她在开始之前会告诉你吗
You think she would have told you that before she started,
想想她的价钱
Considering her price.
非常感激你的安排
Gratitude for arranging this.
朋友之间无需客气
Unnecessary words from a friend.
如果我是你的男人 我一定会让你完成这个仪式
And I being yours, I'll leave you to complete the ritual.
即使传说中的另一个男人
Although tales of this other man
才是你最想要的 只要时间不是问题…
Will be most expected when time is not at issue…
为什么这该死的火把没有点燃？
Why are the fucking torches not lit?
Laelia啊…？
Laelia…?
我欠你一笔债 Ovidius
I owe you a debt, ovidius.
我是来还债的
I've come to repay.
求你了
Please.
那孩子是无辜的
The boy is unstained.
没有任何孩子 在你这种父亲的所作所为下 会是清白的
No child is unstained by the deeds of his father.
他们不是我的人
They are not my own.
Remus派了2个奴隶 想要取走我的性命
Two slaves, sent from remus to take my life.
难道你否认你给了钱？
Do you deny giving coin to the cause?
我是雇了人
I hired the men, yes.
但那是为了实现其他人的目的
But to another's purpose.
谁的？
Whose?
说出他的名字 我向神起誓
Speak the name, and I swear to the gods
我不会杀你
I will not kill you.
是Solonius
Solonius.
他把你欠我的债 都还给了我
He paid the balance of your debt to me.
以此来交换你的死亡
In exchange for me arranging your death.
多谢你的坦白 Ovidius
Gratitude for your honesty, ovidius.
你不会杀了我的 是吧？
You're not going to kill me, then?
不
No.
我的奴隶会杀了你
My slave is going to kill you.
把这该死的地方烧成灰烬
Burn this fucking place to the ground.
但是首先…
But first…
把孩子解决了
Take care of the child.
你是对的
You were right.
我不配呆在这围墙里
I do not honor these walls.
这是众所周知的事实
A fact well known.
对你来说也是这样吗？
Has it always been so for you?
当你第一次被带来这里
When you were brought here for the first time,
并非自愿的时候？
Against your will?
你的命就值几个钱？
Your life traded for a few coins?
不仅仅是几个
More than a few.
那就是你的价值？
Is that your worth, then?
你有没有想过
Has it ever occurred to you
为什么伟大的Theokoles
Why the great theokoles
他的出现 会让我们荣耀万分？
Would grace us with his presence?
对财富的渴望
A promise of wealth.
死亡之影已经赚了很多钱
The shadow has earned a thousand fortunes.
他来此不是为了财富
He comes here not for coin,
而是为了荣誉
He comes here for the glory
和卡普亚战神角斗的荣誉
Of facing the champion of capua.
不可战胜的高卢人
The undefeated gaul.
荣誉
Glory.
没有任何事
There is no greater thing,
比胜利地站在竞技场上 更让人骄傲
Than standing victorious arena.
除了血的较量 就没有其他目标吗？
Is there no purpose beyond the blood?
除了胜利的欢呼 就没有梦想了吗？
No dream beyond the cheering crowd?
没有值得你为之战斗的事了吗？
Is there nothing else you fight for?
Crixus 女主人召见你
Crixus, you are summoned.
走进光里来
Step into the light.
让我仔细看看我们的卡普亚战神
Let me gaze upon the champion of capua.
你真是一个奇迹
You are truly a wonder.
你也是 主人
As are you, domina.
我们没有多少时间了 要好好利用
We don't have much time and I would see it well used.
我没有触发你的激情吗？
Do I not stir you to passion?
是的 主人
Yes, domina.
你的命根不会同意的
Your cock would disagree.
原谅我的心不在焉 主人
Excuse my distraction domina.
我在想明天的事
I have thoughts of tomorrow.
我要让你只想着 深深植入我身体的那一刻
I would have you in the moment, deep inside me.
我从没面对过 像Theokoles这样的对手…
I've never faced an opponent like theokoles…
他也没遇见过 像你一样的男人…
And he has never meet a man like you…
我请求你 主人
I beg a favor domina.
爱情会让一个男人在上战场前变得脆弱…
Love makes a man weak before battle…
我会让你变强壮
I would have you strong.
让我们舍弃一个晚上的欢愉
We will forgo the pleasures of a single evening,
来祈求上天 赐予我们更长久的未来
And pray to the gods for many more to come.
晚安 主人
Domina.
你明天会死吗？
You are going to die tomorrow aren't you?
只有天知道
Only the gods divine the future.
为什么不让Ilithyia帮你？
Why didn't you let ilithyia help you?
她可以和她父亲说…
She could have spoken to her father…
然后呢？
To what end?
换回耻辱？
Humiliation?
尊敬和荣耀
Honor and glory.
这是你唯一在意的 对吗？
That's all you care about, isn't it?
并非全部
Not all.
你还是这么傻
Still the fool.
对啊
Still.
你说过爱会让男人颓丧
You said love drains a man.
如果爱对了人的话 爱能给他希望…
It can give him hope, in the right arms…
你的胜率不大
The odds do not favor you.
向来如此
They seldom do.
我听说Barca在你身上
I've heard barca has laid
下了重注
A large amount of coin on you.
很多人下在Crixus身上 但还是…
More towards crixus, but still…
你呢？
And you?
如果我有钱的话 我会跟着Barca全下掉
If I had the means, I would wager all with barca.
你命太硬 死不了
You're too fucking stubborn to die.
人总有一死
Every man has his end.
我祈祷天神 让你多活几年
I pray to the gods you have not yet reached yours.
如果他们不答应
If they do not answer,
我要请你帮我一个忙
I would ask a thing of you.
我会尽全力去找她
I will do everything I can to find her.
现在 睡吧
Now sleep.
明天你将面对一个传奇人物
Tomorrow you face a legend.
或许你也会成为传奇
And may yet become one yourself.
你看到了吗？！
Did you see it?!
Septimus赢了 我说得没错吧！
Septimus the victor, as I said!
Valarius在进攻的时候 总是忘记拿好盾
Valarius always drops his shield when he attacks,
结果矛一戳 就玩儿完了
A disadvantage against the spear.
这孩子观察力真敏锐
The boy has a keen eye.
谈到角斗士 那倒的确
Towards gladiators, yes.
要是谈到学习 那又是另一回事了
His studies are another matter.
我的名望 已经是历史了
My hour of glory is long past.
你们的名望 有待自己去争取
Yours stands before you.
趁热打铁
Heel old wounds.
杀了那个野种
Kill that fucking son of a whore.
总算到终极勇士的时刻了
Finally, the primus.
这种时刻 总让我口干舌燥
Another moment and my tongue would turn to dust.
上点水
Water.
抱歉 主人
Apologies, domina.
我们没水了
We've used our last.
那么 用点我带来的水吧
Please. Share some of mine.
你考虑得真周到 Solonius
You're too kind, good solonius.
要是可以的话 你也会这样做的
You'd do the same, if you were able.
没关系
No matter.
Theokoles很快会以血祭天
Soon theokoles will honor the gods with blood,
然后 天神就会赐予我们倾盆大雨了
They turn will bless us with endless rain.
但愿如此
I pray for the truth in it.
干旱让城市濒临崩溃了！
This drought is driving the city mad!
收到个噩耗
Unfortunate word has reached us
我们最爱的侄子Ovidius 在家里遇害了
That our dearest cousin ovidius was murdered in his home.
Ovidius吗？
Ovidius?
不会吧
No.
不久前 我才谈起过他太太
I mentioned his wife not a night ago.
那他儿子呢？
What of his son?
他才那么小
He was so young.
他们的房子烧光了 只找到几具尸体
Their villa was burnt, only a few bodies yet recovered.
我怕那孩子也难逃一死
I fear the boy is among the ruins.
真是个悲剧
A tragedy.
到底是谁如此心狠手辣 真奇怪
One cannot but wonder what would prompt such an act.
让我们继续诚心祈雨吧
Let us turn our minds to thoughts of rain,
以解城市酷热的燃眉之急
To cool the fevered brow of our city.
卡普亚的市民们！
Citizens of capua!
罗马的兄弟姐妹们！
Brothers of rome!
以我祖先之名
In the name of my forefathers,
我 Titus Calavius 现在向你们呈献
I, titus calavius, present to you,
终极对决！
The final event!
你的女人 是不是… 血和死亡的壮景
Your woman, is she the reason a spectacle of blood and death,
你活下去的理由？
You refuse to die?
献给谷神的祭品 没错
A sacrifice to ceres, she is.
献给我们最伟大的复兴女神！
The great goddess of renewal!
那么 或许有些东西能胜过荣耀
Then perhaps there is something beyond glory.
赐给我们倾盆大雨！
Shower us with an ocean of rain!
Quintus Lentulus Batiatus家族的勇士上场
From the house of quintus lentulus batiatus.
有请 斯巴达克斯！色雷斯角斗士！
Behold, spartacus! Thraex!
今天参赛的还有 不可战胜的高卢人！
Joined in battle today by the undefeated gaul!
卡普亚战神！
The champion of capua!
有请 Crixus！
Behold, crixus!
高卢角斗士！
Murmillo!
Crixus啊！Crixus！
Crixus! Crixus!
Crixus啊！
crixus!
卡普亚！
Capua!
我们可以开始了吗？
Shall we begin?
和他们决斗的是一个
Together they stand against a man
屡战屡胜的人
Who has never fallen.
一头野性十足的野兽
A beast that has never been tamed.
一个光彩熠熠的传奇人物
A legend that has never been tarnished.
由Marcus Decius Solonius选派
By the grace of marcus decius solonius,
有请！Theokoles！死亡之影！
Behold! Theokoles! The shadow of death!
啊！
Ahh!
开始！
Begin!
他们砍到他了！
They draw blood!
真棒！
Yes!
太棒了！
万岁 卡普亚！
Yeah, capua!
卡普亚！
Capua!
我可以开始了吗？！
Shall I begin?!
滚开
Get out of the way.
滚开 否则我杀了你！
Give ground, or I'll kill you myself!
Theokoles啊！
Theokoles!
杀！杀！杀！
Kill! Kill! Kill!
帅呆了！
Yes!
斯巴达克斯！！
Spar-ta-cus!!